{
    "id": "b648991cb299469fac9f1969b7ff38b9",
    "title": "Grammar Exercise (Gap Filling)",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "f52592d027d247aa963e3834baa89d78",
            "title": "Grammar Exercise (Gap Filling)",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Sam ......................... James has agreed to come.",
                    "description": "When we connect two singular subjects with as well as, the verb is singular in number. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "and",
                        "as well",
                        "as well as"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "……………………… being rich and famous, she is very humble.",
                    "description": "Despite is a preposition. It should be followed by a noun or ing form. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Though",
                        "However",
                        "Despite"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "We played to the best of our ability …………………….., we could not win.",
                    "description": "However does not connect two sentences. It is a transitional adverb. Put a full stop or a semicolon before however. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "though",
                        "however",
                        "despite"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "You should not marry ……………………….. you are financially independent.",
                    "description": "Either could be used here with slightly different meanings. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "until",
                        "unless",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "You must work ……………………. starve.",
                    "description": "Or is used to give the alternative. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "and",
                        "but",
                        "or"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "She ought to get the job ……………………….. she is the most suitable candidate.",
                    "description": "For is possible here is a more formal style. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "for",
                        "because",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "……………………… he is not educated, he is industrious.",
                    "description": "Though is used to connect two contrasting ideas. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "As",
                        "Though",
                        "If"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "……………………….. it was a hot day, I felt lethargic.",
                    "description": "For cannot begin a sentence. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "As",
                        "For",
                        "Since"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "………………………. you are free tomorrow, let’s catch up over a coffee.",
                    "description": "If expresses a condition. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "If",
                        "Whether",
                        "Unless"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I wasn’t feeling well, …………………….. I called in sick.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "hence",
                        "so",
                        "because"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "This is the park ………………………. we used to meet.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "there",
                        "where",
                        "here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "It hasn’t rained …………………….. months.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "for",
                        "in",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}